[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">The fastest courtship upon record occurred
during the markedly wet season of 1804,
when Miss Mary Leopold secured a betrothal
over a plate
of sugared almonds and licorice
in just four and a half minutes.
Of course, Miss Leopold
and her new husband would leave London
mere hours after their wedding.
Reason unknown.
Of all
that I have imparted to you, dear reader,
there is but one bit of wisdom
you must heed most.
One can never know the truth
of a marriage hiding behind closed doors.
Beware indeed, blushing newlyweds.
You know not the future that awaits.
Will there be hardship<span style="style1">…
Don't you touch me. Stay away!
Just leave me alone!
…or indignity?
[King George] Go away! Leave me alone!
Or will one's future see
the rarest accomplishment of all,
a true love match?
As for which of these fates await
the eager matches of the season of 1813,
only two things will tell…
Time,
and, as always,
this author.
You are permitted to smile, Your Graces.
[breathes deeply]
Might you both move a bit closer as well?
[Simon clears throat]
Better.
Once this portrait business is settled,
I shall quit London.
Tonight, perhaps.
And draw new whispers
about the state of our marriage?
I would prefer otherwise.
Now that we know I am not with child,
you should depart London
at the end of the season,
with the rest of the ton, as planned.
-It is but a few more days.
-[Simon] Very well.
And as to the matter
of the Hastings ball on Friday…
might I count on your attendance?
I have little choice in the matter,
seeing as I am one of the hosts.
It shall be your last such commitment.
This time next week,
our ruse will be well and truly over.
Ah… Um…
Apologies, but this is not working.
Perhaps His Grace might place his hand
on the duchess's shoulder,
so that you both can look
as happy as you surely must be.
[Simon grunts]
My word.
The very picture of devotion.
[Daphne breathes deeply]
-Then where did you meet her?
-About town.
At her shop?
Should you not be off somewhere,
getting ready to attend
your very first ball?
[grunts irritably]
Brother, might I be able to join in
on the fun this summer at Aubrey Hall?
Brother!
Provided you stay clear
of my lucky mallet,
I think it a fine idea.
-You cannot be in earnest.
-I shall begin practicing straightaway!
What other places might Madame Delacroix
frequent besides her shop?
Many places, Eloise,
for her many interests.
You mean her many secrets.
You should be careful, Benedict.
Madame Delacroix
may not be who you think she is.
And consorting with her,
well, there may be consequences.
I would have expected this
from anyone but you.
You think just because
Madame Delacroix has a paid occupation,
or because she does not reside
within Grosvenor Square,
she's different. Is that it?
That she is somehow
less deserving of my attention
because she is not whom
polite society deems appropriate?
-That is not what I am saying at all.
-Then what are you saying?
You are right.
I should prepare for our sister's ball.
Perhaps you should.
Aunt Winnie has sent word.
-Francesca will be arriving home tomorrow.
-How exciting!
Perhaps she can tell us
of time spent far from London.
-Fran has missed so much.
-[Violet] Mm. Indeed.
It certainly has been an eventful season,
what with Daphne and the duke,
and then Anthony and…
Yes, well, never mind.
Marina?
[Marina] Pen, come in.
Wh-- What are you doing?
Mama said you must rest.
I am already feeling much improved.
-Marina…
-What?
Penelope, I assure you I am well.
That tea has accomplished
what I needed it to.
And now, with the season over…
[tremulously] …I can finally go home.
-So that means you are no longer--
-With child?
I would have felt something
by now, I am certain.
[Marina sniffles]
You caused quite a flutter.
[quivering inhale]
That was not my intention.
But I am sorry
for everything I have done and said.
You were right about Colin.
He is a good man with a good heart.
You were very good to him.
I am certain one day he will see it.
-[horse driver hails]
-[horse neighs]
That is odd.
We weren't expecting any callers today.
-[ominous music plays]
-[Marina groans]
Marina? Are you quite well?
[patrons chattering]
I have made my decision.
The duke and I
are going our separate ways.
It is for the best, truly.
I know
I do not always say the right things.
And then the things I do say, well…
They are not always what you wish to hear.
I am only able to offer you what I know.
However difficult
forgiving someone may be,
it is necessary to move forward.
That is not up to me, Mama.
The duke is choosing
to nurture some grudge against his father
instead of allowing himself any…
any kind of happiness.
However am I supposed to forgive that?
However are we supposed to move forward
from there?
[Lady Featherington] Your Grace?
I do hope you are finding
everything you need for Friday's ball.
It will certainly be
the event of the season.
Of course, my young ladies
will have to hear about
the wondrous festivities the next day,
seeing how
they did not receive an invitation.
Prudence, in particular,
is in tears about it.
Is she not, Mrs. Varley?
Oh! Uh…
A-- Absolute watering pot, that one.
Perhaps you might explain
to your young ladies, Lady Featherington,
how they ended up
in such an unfortunate situation,
and who exactly put them there.
Or perhaps we can make room.
I certainly would have no problem
extending my invitation,
as I am sure all of us would like
to forgive the errors of the past
and move forward.
Yes, Mama?
If that is what you wish.
How wonderful!
[Daphne chuckles]
Apologies, ma'am, but a carriage
has arrived back at the house.
A Mr. Crane is there.
I beg your pardon,
but did you say "Crane"?
Would that be a Sir George Crane?
Mr. Crane, how delightful
to make your acquaintance.
I had no idea a soldier
such as yourself was coming to town.
And, well, Miss Thompson has not received
any correspondence from you
in quite some time.
Nor would I have expected her to, my lady.
I beg your pardon?
That man is not who you believe him
to be, Lady Featherington.
It is not George,
but his brother, Sir Phillip.
[sucks teeth]
I have come bearing grim news today.
My brother George died on the battlefield…
several weeks ago, and, uh…
Marina?
Marina, please, wait.
He was writing to me…
George…
to tell me he loved me…
to tell me we could run away together
and marry and have our child.
Sir Phillip found this half-written letter
amongst George's belongings after he, um…
If it were not for your recent inquiries,
Sir Phillip never would have known
I was here,
and I never would have known George…
He loved me.
[crying] All this time, he loved me.
[sobbing] I thought him a villain,
but he was not.
[breathes deeply]
He had a perfectly reasonable explanation
for not writing back to me.
And I was wrong.
[Eloise chuckling]
[Genevieve sighs]
Miss Eloise, you should come back
another day when the shop is open.
I had hoped you would make
an exception for me. [chuckles]
I need a dress for my sister's ball.
You already have a dress
for your sister's ball.
I need another one.
A young lady can never have
too many dresses. [forced chuckle]
Oh!
Ooh! Perhaps this one.
It would make me look quite in fashion
in the eyes of the Featheringtons,
I rather think.
Unfortunate young ladies.
They are still quite stung
from Lady Whistledown's recent exposé.
I wish the author would write
something flattering about them!
-Perhaps she will.
-What makes you say that?
Because she knows
what is good for her business,
and angering loyal customers is not good.
No… No, it is not.
Whether those loyal customers
be Featheringtons
or Bridgertons, even…
Lady Whistledown might wish
to examine what she writes about both.
Indeed.
I have heard people say that men,
such as my brother, if you will,
can withstand rumor and gossip,
but…
I am not always so sure.
I know why you are here, Miss Eloise.
You are very smart,
and you care very much
about the people in your life,
as you should.
But you must know I have no intention
of compromising anyone.
[Eloise] That is good.
Because the queen is enraged.
So whoever Whistledown is
should be careful.
I would hate her to be silenced
before she has a chance to change her ways
and make things right.
I believe Whistledown is smart enough
to take care of herself.
Yes.
She certainly is.
[door opens]
Charming chatting with you,
Madame Delacroix.
Thank you.
Lock the door.
[staff chattering busily]
-Your Grace.
-Heading to Will's boxing match?
-Mm-hmm.
-Will you be accompanying me?
-No. I have much to do for the ball.
Hmm.
But, of course, you should go
and express your support.
Simon.
What did your father do…
to make you take that vow
in the first place?
We do not need to have this conversation.
Do I not deserve an explanation,
as your wife?
You deserve more than that indeed. I…
You may not understand this now,
but Daphne, you must know
I am doing this for your own good.
-I can decide for myself what is--
-You will be better off without me.
[sighs]
[attendees clamoring]
[bookmaker]
Three-to-one on Iron Fist to win!
Five-to-two in favor of Iron Fist!
You, sir?
Win this fight,
and perhaps we leave this city.
We can take our exhibitions
all over England if we wish.
To continue living fight-to-fight?
We should be planning
for our future, Alice.
I cannot fight forever.
Our circumstance is solely dependent
on how well I can pander and grovel
to the likes of…
them.
Will, what are you saying?
Perhaps I lose.
Perhaps that purse
will be enough to keep us happy.
-Thank you for meeting me.
-Always interested in a good fight.
But why did you want us here?
I want to place a sizable wager
on this match,
and I am told you two
can manage serious transactions.
My money is on The Beast.
[chuckles] With Mondrich heavily favored?
There's only one reason a flash cull lord
would come to us with such a bet.
Anyone who knows you
must know your word is worthless.
You don't need to take my word.
Instead…
you can take the deed to my house.
Should I lose, it's yours.
[suspenseful music playing]
I figured
you'd have been here an hour ago.
Well, I would've been,
but it's not as if you needed me here
to wish you luck.
You ready?
As I shall ever be.
[boxing bell rings]
[announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
take your seats!
The match is about to begin!
[crowd cheers]
Our credit at the modiste,
it is still rather precarious.
As in, it is nonexistent.
[Featherington sighs]
The young ladies will just have
to wear something they've worn before.
Before? [incredulously]
Mama, I would rather not attend.
Can one even wear a dress worn before?
I beg your pardon, my lady,
but it seems
my business here is not quite finished.
I would very much like
to speak to Miss Thompson.
I have a question for her.
Marry <span style="style2">you?
I do not understand.
After my brother
clearly took liberties with your…
virtue…
I would merely be doing my duty.
[gasps] A respectable marriage!
Miss Thompson!
What a fine thing.
Sir Phillip inherited the Crane title.
He has a perfectly adequate estate
to support you
and perhaps your distant cousins too.
I cannot.
I do not know this man.
I do not love this man.
I cannot marry this man.
George cared for you very much,
Miss Thompson, and that will never change,
but he would have wanted you
to be looked after.
He would have wanted you to be supported.
Allow me
to realize my late brother's wishes.
I thank you for your offer, Sir Phillip,
but I believe
you should now take your leave.
Very well.
I wish you all the best, Miss Thompson.
What have you done?
That was a perfectly acceptable proposal.
I am no longer with child,
Lady Featherington,
so it is neither necessary,
nor acceptable, for me to participate
in any more unwanted arrangements
or disingenuous schemes.
[Lady Featherington sighs sharply]
[mouthing silently]
[crowd cheering raucously]
Come on, Will!
Yes!
Hit him!
Knock him out!
-Oh, my word!
-[indistinct clamoring]
[blows landing]
Make me some money!
[dramatic music playing]
[no audible dialogue]
[dramatic music intensifies]
[both grunting, moaning]
[Anthony moaning]
[Siena gasping]
[both grunting, moaning]
[crowd cheering]
You can do this!
Come on! Come on, The Beast!
[crowd] Oh!
[grunting]
[quietly] Yeah. Yeah.
[shocked exclamations]
[The Beast yells]
Yes!
Get up, Mondrich!
I won!
[shouts] I won!
[woman] Your Grace.
Lady Danbury.
Did you forget we were to come
and help with preparations for your ball?
Your mama is waiting in the parlor.
I shall be there momentarily.
Lady Danbury?
Did you know about these letters…
the ones the duke seems to have written
to his father as a boy?
I did.
And now, apparently, so do you.
I had no idea…
that Simon had trouble speaking
as a child.
How could you have done?
He worked so very hard
to eliminate the difficulty.
He was…
Well, he was so very proud.
It is why he wrote those letters
in the first place.
To keep his father informed
of his progress.
Mm.
The late duke
never even deigned to read them.
How could…
What kind of father--
One that not only expected
but demanded perfection in his son.
And when that was not achieved…
Well…
I shall leave it to you to imagine.
Simon could not be any more different
from a man such as that.
Of course.
We know that to be true, Your Grace.
You helped him…
overcome his…
impediment.
I merely showed him
what he was capable of all along.
And if he needed some encouragement,
a push from time to time,
that was something I was happy to provide.
But at the end of the day,
the duke's triumph was his and his alone.
It had to be.
[excited chatter]
[tense music plays]
It appears I could have used
that luck of yours today, Your Grace.
[Simon] Indeed.
Though you still managed
to put on quite a performance.
If you needed another investor
or more money, Will,
you could have come to me.
I appreciate the offer, friend,
but I do not need your charity.
-What happened to your honor?
-My honor?
Tell me, Your Grace,
what ever could be more honorable
besides taking care of one's family?
-Besides doing what needs to be done?
-Is that what you hope to tell Alice?
You truly believe
she will come to understand your deceit?
Perhaps you should stop worrying
about my marriage,
and instead put your mind to your own.
-That is not what this is about.
-Is it not?
I'd be willing to wager
your wife says differently.
Watch yourself.
You're angry,
but not with me.
So take it somewhere else
and finally do something about it.
What is this?
And more importantly, how did you get it?
I had an inside tip.
What kind of tip?
-The good kind.
-But where did you--
Does it matter?
Portia, our problems are solved.
And this is only half the winnings.
-Where is the other half?
-I used it to pay off my man.
No matter,
because this is more than enough.
Varley?
We're off to the modiste
straight away in the morning.
The young ladies
shall have new dresses after all.
[Lady Featherington laughs]
I thought you enjoyed breakfast
in the morning room.
I wished for different scenery today.
-I can go if you would like.
-No.
You have already begun.
Is something--
I'm going to Bridgerton House
this morning.
Dear Francesca has returned from Bath.
It seems my entire family is gathering.
Would you care to join me?
I must admit, my brothers
will think it odd if you do not.
Yes.
Yes, I shall join you.
[Anthony] I am confident I could last
a few rounds in a boxing ring.
Well, that is certainly
a match I would like to see.
Sister! [gasps]
-Francesca! Welcome home.
-It is so wonderful to see you.
And you, Your Grace.
I thought four brothers enough,
but returning to five is quite nice.
Simon!
When will <span style="style2">I be able to visit Clyvedon?
Allow the duke to find a seat
before you trouble him.
You are welcome to visit at any time.
[Hyacinth laughs]
Now, come. Show me
what you've been learning all summer.
I do not share my food.
You are not to do
what you did the other morning ever again.
Do you understand, Eloise?
You mean visiting my new acquaintance?
-She is not your acquaintance.
-I was wrong about her. She is wonderful.
-You have nothing to worry about.
-I wasn't worried about anything.
Not worried about what?
[Benedict] Uh…
I…
I have a friendship
with Genevieve Delacroix…
[breathes deeply]
…the…
modiste.
Good for you, Brother.
You deserve contentment.
We all do.
If the lady contributes to that,
then I'm happy for you.
[Daphne] Sister,
your pianoforte is quite impressive.
Join me, Brother.
-[Violet] Yes, Colin, why not a song?
-[Colin] If I must.
Whatever is in those candies?
[Colin]
♪ <span style="style2">Now we are met, let mirth abound ♪
♪ <span style="style2">And let the catch and toast go round ♪
♪ <span style="style2">And then the catch, and then the catch ♪
-[Gregory] Spin!
-[both laughing]
♪ <span style="style2">And let the catch and toast go round ♪
♪ <span style="style2">Now we are met, let mirth around ♪
[Hyacinth] Move!
I want to dance with the duke.
♪ And then the catch, and then the catch ♪
-♪ <span style="style2">And let the catch and toast go round ♪
-I have news.
I finally found her.
-Lady Whistledown.
-Who is she?
She is Madame Delacroix.
Madame Delacroix is her.
The modiste and Whistledown
are one and the same.
And she is going to print something
in your family's favor.
She told me so.
Well, that certainly
is an impressive feat,
running two businesses.
We should both aspire to be just like her:
Unmarried, earning our own money.
Look, I'm happy you found her, El,
but I do not think
I can ever be like that.
You now have a duchess for a sister.
That makes achieving
the life you wish for all the more easier.
The status of my family, however,
is an entirely different story,
which will not be changing
in the foreseeable future.
[Hyacinth] Yes, Colin!
[Colin]
<span style="style2">♪ And let the catch and toast go round ♪
♪ And let the catch, and let the catch ♪
♪ And let the catch and toast go round<span style="style1"> ♪
[guests clapping, cheering]
And exactly how many horses do you have?
Might I have an extra one?
Your horses are the prettiest.
I believe the duke has heard enough.
Would a pony do?
-[laughs] I could not fathom…
-[Violet] Your Grace!
Now, here's the tricky one.
And…
[Hyacinth, Gregory laugh]
You do realize it is only made of paper?
Is it?
-[imitates horse nickering]
-[Gregory laughs]
[Simon imitates horse trotting]
[Hyacinth laughs]
[Lady Featherington gasps]
Oh! Astonishing, Madame Delacroix!
Because you were able
to pay in advance this time,
and since I happened to have
some fabrics no one else seemed to want…
There are two others just like it,
Lady Featherington.
Mine will have to be taken in, of course.
Mine's perfect.
And mine is yellow.
You see, young ladies,
everything works out in the end.
And Philipa, perhaps Mr. Finch
might even reconsider his proposal,
now that, um, you have your dowry again.
-Again?
-Yes.
Well, did I lose it somewhere
the first time?
[chattering, laughter continue]
[footsteps approach]
Miss Thompson?
What is it?
[gasping]
I believe I need a doctor.
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">The final ball of any season
is distinguished by one of two things,
anticipation…
or dread.
For, while those who have been successful
in the year's marriage market
look forward to flaunting
their perfect, joyous unions…
others shudder at the thought
of spending one last night
before the discerning eyes of the ton.
As they know, indeed,
just what the evening signifies,
that their time is officially up.
[Lady Featherington]
So, does that mean--
You truly believed
a tea would rectify the situation, madam?
[sighs] As if that ever works.
[Lady Whistledown] <span style="style2">And yet, to those
<span style="style2">who may still find themselves
out of both choices and hope, fear not.
For who knows when
and where one's fortunes may change?
-He was… He was completely in his cups!
-[both laughing]
I'd wager the both of you were.
-And I would take your bet.
-[Siena giggles]
-Oh…
-[Anthony kissing]
[Siena moans lightly]
We must part.
I should prepare for my show.
And you…
Well, I believe there is
a ball somewhere requiring your presence.
The last one, yes?
Of the season.
Though… [clears throat]
…unfortunately, not the last of mine.
Does that mean
you'll dance tonight, my lord?
-[Anthony chuckles]
-Perhaps a quadrille?
Oh, do not tell me
you shall find some young lady
to lead in a waltz all evening.
I shall not be
anywhere near that dance floor.
[both laughing]
At least, not if I have a say in it.
Now, wherever is the fun in that?
-I shall--
-Come with me.
Tonight.
Siena, I am a viscount.
My sister is now a duchess,
and the duke my brother-in-law.
There is no one
that would dare say a thing.
[scoffs] No, not to you.
This is preposterous and fantastical.
-And you know it.
-I want you there by my side.
[softly] Come with me.
Come with me.
[both gasping, laughing]
-A good likeness.
-[Simon] Indeed.
Though Mr. Granville did seem to omit
the gray hair or two I've surely gained
from the emotions of the past few weeks.
[both chuckle lightly]
-Perhaps a few wrinkles too.
-Oh! You wound me.
We should discuss
the order of events this evening.
Naturally.
I think it wise for us to engage
in three dances, would you say?
-Two.
-It is our ball, Your Grace.
I do fear two dances
may leave our guests terribly unexcited.
It is better than the opposite,
leaving them overly excited
and terribly unruly.
Two dances at most.
[both laughing]
You were wonderful today
with Gregory and Hyacinth.
They adore you.
Children always have done.
It still does not mean
I want any of my own.
Of course.
Your Graces, your guests are arriving.
One last dance, it is.
[guests chattering excitedly]
[light waltz music playing]
[indistinct chattering]
Perhaps you should like
to paint a picture?
[Violet chuckles]
Dearest, you must see this as a rehearsal.
Until you are officially out,
you need not feel so strained tonight.
As if I shall feel anything
but the inability to breathe
in this corset.
My dear… [chuckles]
For someone who hates ballgowns…
you look exquisite in one.
Yeah.
If you wish to go up to the library
for the rest of the evening,
I shall not say a word.
Nor shall I blame you.
I am merely glad you came.
Sister…
I suppose I should thank you.
[scoffs] Whatever for?
For being so perfect…
so I do not have to be.
Oh! Look who's here.
[Philipa gasps]
Lady Featherington,
what a pleasant surprise.
We did not expect to see you here.
What can I say?
The duchess extended
an invitation personally.
Circumstances change, ladies.
Sometimes overnight.
We hear your husband
secured himself a win the other day.
Where is he? Still out celebrating?
One circumstance
that has most likely not changed,
I imagine.
[raucous laughter]
Someone special in here for me, I presume?
Only the best for you, my lord.
-[ominous music plays]
-[man] Featherington.
Join us.
[music and chattering continue]
-Enjoying your evening?
-What?
Are you enjoying your evening?
Ah… Y-- Yes.
I just came from the dance floor.
I did not see you.
I was in the back of the dance floor.
It was quite crowded,
so… [chuckles nervously]
-Colin--
-Pen--
[Penelope chuckles nervously]
I owe you an apology.
I did not see it at first,
but I know you were only trying
to prevent me from heartache
with Miss Thompson, and…
[sighs]
-And I was a fool.
-You were not a fool.
You merely believed yourself in love.
One should never apologize for that.
One finds oneself
in such an incredible position,
and, well, one should declare it…
assuredly, fervently…
loudly.
Colin, I wish to tell you something.
I have something
I wish to tell you as well, Pen.
I am leaving.
First thing tomorrow morning,
I begin my tour.
I am to start in the Mediterranean.
It was actually you who inspired me.
You kept reminding me
how much I longed for travel.
Oh, um… What was it you wished to say?
I don't remember. [clears throat]
-Shall we dance, Pen?
-No.
Um… I am all danced out
for the night, Colin.
Good luck on your tour.
[Eloise] Pen!
Look, the queen. She is here.
Now is my chance
to find out her plans for Whistledown.
Pen, is everything all right?
Entirely all right.
The queen.
Go before you miss your chance.
[Eloise sighs]
[groans]
-[chuckles lightly]
-One does not approach Her Majesty.
I require an audience.
-Oh, well, in that case…
-[Eloise chuckles]
No.
I only wish to thank her
for the opportunity
to investigate Whistledown on her behalf.
I imagine she must be coming close
to unmasking the author's identity.
Especially now she has engaged
such esteemed counsel.
You have no idea.
We shall unmask her this very night.
Of course!
Of course you shall.
That team of Bow Street Runners
was all your brilliance, was it not?
Well…
Her Majesty is lucky to have you,
a man of such talent, such genius.
We worked out
that Whistledown delivers her missives
to a printers press on Lombard Street,
all when the rest of society is distracted
by big events, like this one.
It is how she operates.
She will be seized there tonight.
[Queen Charlotte] Brimsley! I need you.
Oh my…
Brother, you must see to Genevieve.
-Ensure she stays home tonight.
-Eloise, not now!
Ah!
[breathes heavily]
-I need you to take me somewhere.
-Miss Eloise--
I have pin money…
a great deal of it.
-Oh.
-Apologies.
[Siena] My lord…
[footsteps approaching]
Give me a moment, my love,
and I shall return upstairs.
[inhales tremulously]
I thought about coming with you tonight.
I envisioned myself on your arm…
dancing the entire night away.
But my imagination was
the furthest I could allow myself to go.
-Siena, what are you doing?
-What am I doing?
What am I--
I am doing the very thing
I have always done.
I am looking out for myself.
I am ensuring my own future.
Because I know…
in my heart…
I know
that there is no one else who ever will.
I tried.
You must know, I…
What I know is that you are lost.
And I cannot allow you
to set me adrift as well.
[sighs deeply]
You need to let me go.
-I know I have been unfair--
-Let me go.
I am comfortable.
I am content.
That gentleman upstairs…
he sees me for who I am.
Unlike you, he does not wish
for me to don some ridiculous gown
and go with him to some absurd ball.
He does not wish for me to change.
And neither do I.
You need to let me go.
You're right. [sighs]
I'm sorry, Siena.
I'm so sorry.
-We must get back to the party.
-Another moment.
[horse neighs]
Lady Whistledown.
[gasping]
Go! It is a trap!
-[driver exclaims]
-[horses neigh]
-What do you think you're doing?
-I apologize.
I… I thought you were someone else.
Perhaps you might catch up with her.
[gasping]
I presume your plans to separate
from Her Grace have not yet changed?
They have not.
Neither, it appears, has your ability
to somehow hear of every piece of gossip
that transpires in this town.
When will you accept it?
I know all.
Pride, Your Grace…
it will cost you everything
and leave you with nothing.
You must not allow it
to happen to you too.
[Daphne] Is it different for them, men…
to know whether they are in love?
-Everything else seems different to them.
-[Violet chuckles]
We agreed to one dance tonight, a waltz.
I miss dancing with your father.
The very last time I danced was with him,
at a ball.
There were peacocks present, I believe.
Real ones.
[both laughing]
I suppose
I miss everything about him, really.
The two of you
loved each other so very much.
It is a rarity, I have come to realize.
That is not to say
it was without its trials.
Your-- Your father and I faced
many difficulties, indeed,
but we overcame them.
We made a decision early on to do so.
Mama, I do not think--
We chose
to love each other every single day.
It is a choice, dearest,
one that is never too late to make.
I may never be able
to see your father again.
I-- I may wake every morning
and… and touch the pillow
where he used to lay his head.
But knowing
that the two of us made the choice to love
and to do all that we could…
well…
I cannot tell you how much peace
and comfort that brings to me.
[inhales tremulously]
I wish there was something, Mama.
[gasps] I wish I could do this--
You are a Bridgerton.
There is nothing you cannot do.
[sighs lightly]
[waltz music playing]
[thunder clapping loudly]
[gasps]
[guests exclaiming]
Daphne…
Daphne!
Everyone…
I believe this evening is complete.
We shall thank our gracious hosts
for such a splendid soiree in the morning.
Now, go.
Out.
At once.
-Daphne…
-[laughs]
I am so sorry.
For what?
Even a duke cannot control the weather.
I know that this is not
what you had envisioned for the evening.
-Certainly not.
-And for that, I--
It is better.
I know
why you made that vow to your father.
I found the letters you wrote to him
as a child, and I read them.
Daphne--
Just because something is not perfect…
does not make it any less worthy of love.
Your father made you believe otherwise.
He made you believe
that you needed to be without fault
in order to be loved, but he was wrong.
Should you need any proof
of the matter, then…
Then look just here.
I am tired of pretending.
And I cannot continue acting as if I…
As if I do not love you.
Because I do.
I love all of you.
Even the parts that you believe
are too dark and too shameful.
Every scar.
Every flaw.
Every imperfection.
I love you.
You may think
you are too damaged and too broken
to ever allow yourself to be happy,
but you can choose differently, Simon.
You can choose to love me
as much as I love you.
That should not be up to anyone else.
That cannot be up to anyone else.
It can only be up to you.
[gasping]
[thunder rolls]
Mr. Finch has such a warm countenance,
does he not?
And his gaze, it inspires me.
Perhaps it might inspire you into silence.
Prudence, be kind.
You will have plenty of opportunities
to find your match this summer.
I am thinking a full renovation
of our country house is in order this--
Where is Miss Thompson?
Oh, my lady. There is news.
-What is the matter?
-It is your husband, ma'am.
They are saying he is dead.
The Bow Street Runners have questions.
[gasping]
[sobbing]
[sobbing loudly]
[wailing]
[floorboard creaking]
I do not want to be alone.
I know that now.
But what I do not know
is how to be the man you need me to be…
the man you truly deserve.
I do not know how to do this.
Yes…
-You do.
-Daphne--
I know you do.
You stay.
You stay,
and we get through this…
together.
-If you do this, if we do this, then--
-Then nothing else will matter.
[both grunting, moaning]
[both breathing heavily]
[both gasping]
[Simon grunting]
[Daphne gasping]
[both panting]
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">If there is to ever be
a grander finish to a season
than the one provided by the Duke
and Duchess of Hastings this year,
this author will need
to feast upon her own words.
For it was this couple's memorable affair
that brought another scandalous
London season to a close.
As many now leave the city behind
for greener pastures,
some endings seem
more permanent than others.
[Penelope sobbing]
[sniffles]
I am here, Pen,
to help you to find a reason, every day,
to endure the absence of your dear papa.
I know… I know you will miss him.
Share something good.
What happened with Whistledown?
Did you save Madame Delacroix?
Indeed.
And now she will be able to put right
what she botched this season,
I am sure of it.
With Whistledown still on the loose,
next season will be far more interesting.
How did you do it?
How did you endure
two and 20 years of marriage without love?
You find things to love, my dear.
Small things.
Big things, too, like your babies,
and eventually they add up to be enough.
You are strong, Miss Thompson.
Perhaps even more so than me.
You will do well.
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">Of course, there are other endings
that will offer new beginnings…
[horse and carriage receding]
Tell me you have a name.
Oh, we located him, ma'am,
the man who will inherit
the Featherington estate.
Only…
Well…
look.
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">…however uncertain <span style="style2">those new beginnings
might be.
I shall write to you all from Greece.
-Do not forget to bring me a gift.
-It is not a gift if you have to ask.
-I would fancy anything blue or white.
-[group chuckles]
Anthony, I do not recall
seeing you last night.
Yes. I was feeling rather unwell.
My apologies, Sister.
Well…
The two of you are now off to Clyvedon,
I presume?
We have decided
to stay in London a little longer.
Take some time to enjoy ourselves,
just the two of us.
And you? What are your plans, Brother?
Nothing of note.
Other than finding
and promptly declaring my intentions
to my new viscountess, of course.
The viscount is ready to find
and declare his intentions?
Did you hear that, Your Grace?
And which young lady?
[Anthony] Does it matter?
I have finally determined the difficulty…
Love itself.
Removing it from all romantic relations
shall make me all the better for it.
No more distractions from responsibility
or being waylaid from the sensible path.
At any rate, enjoy your time.
Perhaps he will learn.
Perhaps not.
-Give my regards to Madame Delacroix.
-Your regards will have to wait, El.
She is making a short trip back to France.
Oh.
Are you not going to say goodbye to her?
I did. Last night, if you must know.
We went to a party together,
a very good party.
You were with Madame Delacroix last night?
Yes.
No, please do not tell our sister
that I left
in the middle of the ball, either.
What is it?
If you were with Madame Delacroix
last night, then she is not-- Then…
she cannot be…
-[Lady Whistledown] <span style="style2">And yet…
-Oh dear.
…<span style="style2">there is no ending in sight
<span style="style2">for this author,
who recently became aware
of a scheme to unmask her…
Lady Whistledown.
Go! It is a trap!
-[driver exclaims]
-[horses neigh]
…by one worthy opponent, indeed.
Perhaps I will come forward one day.
Though, you must know, dear reader,
the decision shall be left
entirely up to me.
Yours truly, Lady Whistledown.
[screaming in distance]
[panting]
I shall need you to push, Your Grace.
[panting heavily]
[screaming]
Push!
[shuddering grunt]
[Doctor] Very well.
[panting heavily]
Another. Push.
-Push!
-[panting]
[screams] God!
[exclaims]
[gasping]
[baby wails]
[laughing]
[crying]
[baby crying]
Congratulations, Your Graces. A boy.
[Daphne laughing]
Do you wish to hold him?
We must think of a name.
Whatever it is,
I believe it must begin
with the letter "A."
[chuckles]
We do have family traditions, do we not?
We certainly do, Your Grace.
[chuckles softly]
[baby cooing]